

Abdulghani Akhras

- Donegal. Ireland
- +353-894 720 061
- akhras.abd@gmail.com
- http://abod.pro

Languages





Achivements

French







German





Interestes

Travelling





Cooking

Painting

Gaming



I am one of the passionate software engineers who seek to create a smarter tomorrow, my unique set of skills and motivations drives to innovate and create epic things that make the world a better place. I am specialised in: Full-Stack Web Development, UI/UX Design and cross-platform applications development. I am Fluent in a number of programming languages including JavaScript, PHP, Java, C, C++ among a few others, which looks like a perfect package to be.

I am self-motivated, flexible and able to handle a broad range of tasks, have good problem solving abilities and am hard working and team orientated. I am able to comply with all relevant technical standards, and have a proven track record of delivering all specified tasks outcomes on time, within the quality required. Because I love what I do I strive to be the best in my position, this attitude gives me an appreciation of the bigger business picture, and not just a company's IT requirements. The passion for creating products that leave memorable experiences, having the opportunity to do so is what keeps me motivated each and every day.



EDUCATION

Baccalaureate



Engineering in Communication Technology

GPA: 3.96



GPA: 3.89

Bachelor in Information & Communication Technology



JOB EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer

Design ideas/solutions, and manage, monitor and maintain the computer systems and network

dip dip

2015

Front End Specialist

Developing and supporting various critical applications for the enterprise: like: RPE, GIFT, DCI, AHP and FFP.

Pramerica

DECEMBER

201

Software Engineer

Developing Web Applications from the ground up; architected component modules and database.

Lava Labs

TECHNOLOGY SKILLS

JavaScript

Node.js (Express)

Angular Framework

HTML5 & CSS3

React.js Framework

MySQL & MongoDB

PHP

Java

Adobe Photoshop

Adobe Illustrator

Photography

Adobe Premiere Pro

Wordpress

Unit Testing (Protractor) Git

Portfolio

ROLE

Front End Specialist

Pramerica Prudential PRUDENTIAL APPLICATIONS

TECHNOLOGIES

Angular, AngularJS, NodeJS, Sass, framework and Twitter Bootstrap

Dec 2017 - Present

- Working with the latest Web development technologies such as Angular, NodeJS, Sass, framework and Twitter Bootstrap.
- Build and test new or extend existing components for the official Prudential Angular Library, working with concepts such as progressive enhancement, mobile first and future friendly design.
- Collaborate with Back End Developers on API Design for RESTful web services.
- Working in an Agile environment delivering new components as well as aiding the development of new products.
- Developing, implementing and supporting various mission critical applications for the Enterprise and its Business units, such as: GIFT, RPE, DCI, AHP and FFP.
- Delivering a complex piece of code for Alerts and notifications. The reusable component I created has been used across multiple other teams.

ROLE

Web Developer



TECHNOLOGIES

AngularJS, JAVA, JavaScript, Carto, Google-Maps, Css3, jQuery

GAS MALAYSIA SYSTEM FEB 2017 - SEP 2017

(Front-End & Back-End)

Gas Malaysia provides clean, efficient and stable supply of Natural Gas and Liquefied Petroleum Gas to homes, commercial businesses and industries. Their energy solutions include power generation system with heat recovery such as Combined Heat & Power and alternative gas distribution such as virtual pipeline. It provide custom solutions that will perfectly and repeatedly meet their customer needs. Such a tailored approach is both time-consuming and costly.

They wanted a huge site to empower Sales and Marketing staff to geospatially map and visualize customer's different types of data sets, with an overlaid existing pipeline data and visual drawing of proposed pipeline to estimate potential customer's infrastructure investment cost, construction timeline and calculate Internal Rate of Return (IRR) on the go. This in turn would provide business insights into how Gas Malaysia may maximize revenue within a certain district, or perhaps strategically decide whether or not to invest in a given area. This project was probably the biggest challenge as it has a huge number of different functions, to make everything run smoothly and cohesively was a huge win.

ROLE

Front-End Development & Salesforce Configuration



Aviation Commission

CONSUMER AFFAIRS SYSTEM

JAN 2017 - FEB 2017

TECHNOLOGIES

Salesforce, Css3, JavaScript

The Malaysian Aviation Commission (MAVCOM) is an independent entity to regulate economic and

OVERVIEW

TECH

commercial matters related to civil aviation in Malaysia. Their goal is to promote a commercially viable, consumer-oriented and resilient civil aviation industry which supports the nation's economic growth. Their approach was customer focused, and by looking at the needs of the users I were able to meet

the frustrations and complaints of their users head on. So creating, responsive and adaptive website and making sure the content is easily accessible and navigable. So customers intuitively find services and information for their specific needs. The structure built of working with customers helps MAVCOM build long lasting relationships.

OVERVIEW

Front-End Development & Graphic Design

FIRST

TECHNOLOGIES

JavaScript, Css3, jQuery, Wordpress, PHP, Adobe Illustrator

FirstClasse Website

Sep 2016 - Dec 2016

OVERVIEW

OVERVIEW

A digital media agency providing unique access to an exclusive luxury member base. It has focus on Fashion & Beauty, Cars & Gadgets, Watches & Jewellery, Travel & Homes, and Lifestyle. Simply on all the good and positive things in life. The website visualizes these things every day with the intention to inspire and motivate people to achieve their goals. And it provides unique advertising opportunities to brands.

Creating an experience that is captivatingly unique, and also informative. Which stand out from everyday websites, yet it is accessible and intuitive to use from any device, and for any of the broad range of people that would access. This also included designing for extremes, such as not knowing which or how much information would be on the website. Whenever I design something different like this, I make sure I've actually vetted it out thoroughly in terms of front-end implementation to make sure the website would fit all sorts of different screen sizes perfectly. The website has a trendy and elegant css transitions, it built to guarantee smooth web and mobile performance.

ROLE

Project Lead (Front-End & Back-End) PRIVASIA

Fleet Management System

June 2016 - Sep 2016

TECHNOLOGIES

JavaScript, CSS3, PHP, Google Maps, MySQL,Slim, jQuery

Privasia have developed a portfolio of applications and solutions to enhance business processes and best practices. Their Spend Management offers services consisting of eBidding (Reverse Auction and Forward Auction), eProcurement (eRFQ/eTender) and Vendor Sourcing. They also provide outsourcing services with their 4 main pillars; collaboration, knowledge and focus, independence, and value.

Building a truck monitoring system to geofence trucks in order to track their transit progress between different depots. In addition, a web monitoring system which centered in the Privasia's various depots that allows depots to view the amount of truck traffic that is moving in and out of their facility at any given point of time. Providing three representations of the datas. Real time, Visual and CSV Reports. I led the development of Privasia system at all scales, from System Architecture, Web Design, Mobile API and the Web App.



Maybank Website POC

Maybank is the fourth largest bank in South East Asia, with total assets of more than RM722 billion. Maybank Group is the leading financial services provider in Malaysia catering to the needs of consumers, investors, entrepreneurs, non-profit organisations and corporations. The Group, which

Apr 2016 - June 2016

TECHNOLOGIES

HTML5, Css3, JavaScript, Photoshop

VERVIEW

has expanded internationally, has the largest network among Malaysian banks of over 2,400 branches and offices in 20 countries, employing over 44,000 Maybankers and serving over 22 million customers. It is the only regional bank with a presence in all 10 ASEAN countries.

With over 3m unique visitors, Maybank2U is the most popular Malaysian website. However, its design is not that great. It looks like a site designed in the 90s. The website involved a lot of re-designing and UI/UX fixes to incorporate a modern look, responsive layouts and better UX for

And I pitched several different approaches that echo a refreshed look and feel for the website.

Those changes could push the website from just being usable to being delightful.

mobile devices. As the website and its content was really outdated I started the project listing the unnecessary content and making it simpler and shorter, to catch the user attention to the main tabs.